PERSONAL INFORMATION

Jesús Huete Cubillo



😯 Ventura Rodríguez, 9 - 3ºA, 29009, Málaga (Spain)

690 098 392

🔀 j.huetecubillo@gmail.com 👔

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jesushuete

Nationality Spanish

OCCUPATION

January 2021 to Nowadays

R&D Engineer

Bettergy | Parque Tecnológico de Andalucía. Avda. Juan López Peñalver nº17, Planta 3ª, ala B. 29590 Málaga. https://www.bettergy.es

Technical specifications to be implemented in Energy Sequence (a web platform for intelligent management of energy). Research and development tasks in the field of energy efficiency and power systems. Energy analysis and consulting. Product development. Innovation opportunities.

Business or sector Electrical Engineering & Energy Efficiency

November 2020 to Nowadays

Collaborating Researcher

Research group OASYS (Optimization and Analytics for Sustainable Energy Systems) at University of Malaga | Edificio Ada Byron – Calle Arquitecto Francisco Peñalosa 18, 29071 Málaga. https://sites.google.com/view/groupoasys

Framework collaboration agreement between the University of Malaga, the research group OASYS and the host technology company Bettergy for the development of my doctoral thesis with industrial mention. Shared knowledge, tools and data sources.

Business or sector Research and science

EDUCATION

November 2020 to Nowadays **PhD student in Electrical Power Systems**

School of Industrial Engineering | University of Malaga

October 2019 to Nowadays

MA in Intelligent Systems in Energy and Transport

School of Industrial Engineering | University of Malaga

October 2016 to September 2019

MA in Mathematics

School of Sciences | Universities of Malaga & Granada

October 2016 to June 2017 MA in Secondary School Training (speciality Mathematics)

School of Education Sciences | University of Malaga

September 2012 to June 2015 M.Sc. Industrial Organisation Engineering

School of Industrial Engineering | University of Málaga

September 2005 to December 2011 **B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering**

School of Technical Engineering | University of Córdoba

WORK EXPERIENCE

February 2020 to April 2020

Research Assistant

Research group MICROSOL (Smart Solar Micro-exchangers) at University of Malaga | ETS Ingeniería de Telecomunicaciones – Bulevar Louis Pasteur, 35, 29071 Málaga. https://eventos.uma.es/29984/detail/microsol.html

Collaboration in the assembly of the home automation elements of prototypes of Smart solar micro-exchangers for sustainable mobility. Review of design aspects. Tests and trials on the web platform.

Business or sector Research and science

March 2019 to September 2019 **Research Assistant**

Research group OASYS (Optimization and Analytics for Sustainable Energy Systems) at University of Malaga | Edificio Ada Byron – Calle Arquitecto Francisco Peñalosa 18, 29071 Málaga. https://sites.google.com/view/groupoasys

Application of data science for the sustainability and optimization of power systems and the search for strategies and tools to promote the use of renewable energies. Analysis of the demand response.

Business or sector Research and science

July 2017 to July 2018 **Organizational Engineer**

Quality and innovation Department at Málaga City Council – Avenida Cervantes 4, 29016 Málaga. http://www.malaga.eu

Planning, control and management of organizational improvement projects and technological innovation. Simplification and optimization of processes. Technical reports and statistical studies.

Business or sector Public Administration

November 2011 to May 2012

Production Engineer

Asea Brown Boveri, S.A. - Carretera Almodóvar, 14004 Córdoba. http://new.abb.com/es

Quality control and work organization. Computer mechanical design. Technical specifications and user guides. Stock management and commercial tasks with suppliers and customers.

Business or sector Industrial Engineering

December 2010 to June 2011 **Technical Engineer**

Baena City Council - Plaza de la Constitución 1, 14850 Baena (Córdoba). http://www.baena.es

Development of technical projects: plans, measurements, and budgets. Industrial facilities in buildings and new constructions. Technical reports of industrial and commercial establishments.

Business or sector Public Administration

LANGUAGES

Mother tongue

Spanish

Other languages

English: Fluent (Certificated CEFR level C)

French: Basic level

STAY ABROAD

July 2016

European Voluntary Service (Romans International, France)

A social inclusion project in Romans. I worked with the associations Emmaüs (second-hand store) and Bricothèque (restoration of buildings) to help disadvantage people and less resources.

September 2014 to February 2015 Erasmus Plus EU Mobility Programme (Brno University of Technology, Czech Republic)

School of Electrical Engineering and Communication and School of Business and Management.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication skills

Clarity and concision. Empathy. Good and friendly treatment with people. Willing to join easily to any environment job. Good level of scientific-technical expression.

Organization & management skills

Organisational and leadership capacity. Facility to be employed group. Formality and strictness in work. Proactive. Methods of organization and planning of tasks.

Computer skills

Microsoft Office 365 | CYPECad | CYPETherm | CYPELux | AutoCAD | Presto | Dialux | SolidWorks | Dmelect | Calculux | IFC Builder | Geomedia | Cabri | Sage | LimeSurvey | Matlab | Labview | InTouch | Python | R-studio | Gams | Latex

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Publications

Sizing and operation of a residential PV-battery system: Rule-Based and real time vs optimization and perfect foresight | Conference Paper in MELECON 2020 (June 2020)

Projects

Data Science in the analysis of the power demand | Final Master Project (September 2019)
The use of ICT in mathematical network learning | Final Master Project (June 2017)
Business plan to develop an organic olive oil processing plant | Final Degree Project (June 2015)
Industry dedicated to metallic carpentry and artistic forge | Final Degree Project (December 2011)

Training courses

Design & simulation of deep neural networks using Keras & Tensorflow / June 2019 / 3 hours Improvement of energy efficiency in buildings / October - December 2018 / 300 hours

Web pages design / February - March 2018 / 30 hours SEO and SEM / January - March 2018 / 30 hours

Advanced EXCEL / February 2018 / 30 hours

Labour risk prevention / January - March 2017 / 60 hours

Web analytics / October 2016 / 40 hours

Design and implementation of plans and measures equality / March - April 2016 / 65 hours

Digital Marketing March 2016 / 40 hours

Matlab for engineers and scientists / July 2013 / 25 hours

International cooperation. Agents, policies, and areas of action / May 2012 / 50 hours Data protection and security of personal information / April - May 2012 / 80 hours

Urban environment / March - April 2011 / 100 hours

Design, shaped and calculation of structures for computer / February 2011 / 80 hours

Awards

DARDO Management System | 2nd award in the Innovation Competition of Málaga City Hall (May 2017) **Mobile App BaenaCheck** | 1st award in Live Ideas Baena Contest to young people (June 2015) **Youth Project Baen@ctiva** | 1st award in Live Ideas Baena Contest to young people (May 2014)